They wanted her face down, ass up, hands cuffed and ankles strapped. They wanted her knowing she could never want them back. Oh, they wanted her holy, baptized in her divine, they wanted her secrets, pearls to swine. They wanted to unravel the mystery of her design. Fascinated by glory, hypnotized by her kind. Oh, they wanted her complete. They wanted her whole, though they came fractioned, half-hearted, half-soul, with no regards and no knowledge as to who she really was. Oh, but if they knew. If they knew her, praise songs would rain from the clouds of their eyes, clearing the vision, bathing the heart. They would bow every time they saw her. Be their best selves when she was around. If they knew her, knew she was the glue to their revolution, the life flow of blood through their veins. If they knew her, she would know, she would feel that her body is more than battlefield. More than bone break and bleeding bigotry. More than bridge over your troubled conscience. More than used up, walked on, driven through, shot up. More than your "Selma, Lord, Selma" Edmund Pettus. More than your killer Katrina Danziger.
La querían bocabajo, con le culo en pompa, esposada, atada. La querían sabiendo que ella nunca los querría. Oh, la querían santa, bautizada en su divinidad, querían sus secretos, margaritas para los cerdos. Querían desenmarañar el misterio de su diseño. Fascinados por la gloria, hipnotizados por su clase. Oh, la querían completa. La querían entera, aunque ellos vinieron fraccionados, mitad corazón, mitad alma, sin miramientos ni conocimientos sobre quién era de verdad. Oh, pero si lo supieran. Si la conocieran, lloverían alabanzas en canciones de las nubes de sus ojos, despejando la visión, bañando el corazón. Harían reverencias cuando la vieran. Darían lo mejor de sí a su alrededor. Si la conocieran, sabrían que era el pegamento de su revolución. El curso de la vida de la sangre en sus venas. Si la conocieran, ella sabría, ella sentiría, que su cuerpo es más que el campo de batalla. Más que el hueso roto y fanatismo sangriento. Más que un puente sobre tu conciencia aquejada. Más que gastado, andado, devorado y disparado. Más que tu "Selma, Lord, Selma" Edmund Pettus. Más que tu asesina: Katrina Danziger.
More than your bust them out of Baltimore "Highway to Nowhere." If they knew her, she would know. (Singing) Wild women, wild women, they walk with buffalo. Have lightning on their tongues, fly whisks as weapons. Wild women, they walk with machetes. With wisdom, with grace, with ease. Wild women have hurricanes in their bellies, releasing a flood of a lesson. Oh, wild women, they fly free. Just watch their ways, how they rip and shred. Oh, who can understand her, this winding Niger river of a woman one who is unafraid to tear away only to roam and then become the wind. She who speaks in gusts and cyclones blasting us back to high ground, high consciousness, she turns and so does the world. Feel her spinning, spanning several lifetimes. Hear her speaking, sparking alarm. See her dancing, summoning the dead, resurrecting new life. Heaven hears her knocking on the door, safely transporting the ones who call for her assistance. Wild women, they open portals to new worlds, new speech, new dreams. Oh, dearly beloveds, so dearly departed from the ways of the guardian, beware. For wild women are not to be tamed. Only admired. Just let her in and witness her set your days ablaze.
Más que tu fúgate de Baltimore "Highway to Nowhere". Si la conocieran, ella lo sabría. (Cantando) Mujeres salvajes, mujeres salvajes, caminan con búfalos. Tienen relámpagos en la lengua, sacuden escobas como armas. Las mujeres salvajes andan con machetes. Con sabiduría, con elegancia, con calma. Las mujeres salvajes tienen huracanes en el vientre, que liberan inundaciones de enseñanzas. Oh, las mujeres salvajes vuelan libres. Observa sus caminos, sus rasgados jirones. Oh, quién puede entenderla, a ella que es el sinuoso río Níger uno que no tiene miedo de atreverse solo para vagar y convertirse en el viento mismo. Ella que habla en ráfagas y ciclones haciéndonos volar de vuelta a la tierra, alta conciencia, se da la vuelta y el mundo también, Siente como gira, abarcando varias vidas. Escúchala hablar, alarma chispeante. Mírala bailar, invocando a la muerte, resucitando nueva vida. El cielo la escucha llamar a sus puertas, transportando con cuidado a los que buscan su ayuda. Las mujeres salvajes abren portales a mundos nuevos, discursos nuevos, sueños nuevos. Oh, queridos míos, qué queridos fallecieron lejos de los caminos del que les guarda, tengan cuidado. Porque a las mujeres salvajes no se las puede dominar. Tan solo admirar. Déjala entrar y sé testigo de cómo quema tus días.
(Cheers) (Applause) Thank you. (Applause)
(Aclamación) (Aplausos) Gracias. (Aplausos)